<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Peter &amp; Nick</title>
  
  <subtitle>Keeping Up With Dakardashians</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-01-12T09:06:43.243Z</updated>
  <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Peter Forberg &amp; Nicholas Earley</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Un Vrai Ami</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/12/Un-Vrai-Ami/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/12/Un-Vrai-Ami/</id>
    <published>2020-01-12T09:05:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-12T09:06:43.243Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>At Sandaga Market, the sharks eat the minnows.</p><p>Here’s the sun, setting over flat, low roofs. People do not live here; people sell. Pharmacies, hotels, restaurants, and clothing stores reign supreme, their terraces devoid of clotheslines and goat pens. When the fire goes out, there are no lamps to guide your way. It is darkness, starlit and cold, without passing dining room candles to spark alleyways, all windows converted into pull-down metal doors that eschew light and loitering. Only the passing motorbike, swerving out of sand heaps, will perforate the black streets, dust defining its cyclops headlight’s diffusion. But there is little diffusion. Even the light huddles close together, like tourists fooled by the long days now suspicious of the sudden night. Sunsets are short, daylight deceptive.</p><p>Here’s the roundabout, an infinite loop of taxi drivers shipping and receiving the day’s latest catches. Most emerge confident, vanishing into the crowd, deftly dispatching peddlers and market guides. “J’ai pas d’argent,” they say, as they enter a market.</p><p>But here are the minnows. They’re spotted even before the taxi drops them off. They’re spotted by the police officers who lounge in the traffic’s center, they’re spotted by the shoppers who know family from foreigners, and they’re spotted by the sharks, who rise with glowing smiles and hearty laughs, dollar signs in their eyes. <em>La peau blanche.</em></p><p>They will ask you all the same questions, like “where are you from?” and “can you speak any Wolof?” and “what are you looking for today?” <em>I’m just looking.</em> They’ll practice their English on you, and they’ll feign annoyance at the other peddlers who would merely offer you their goods. You’ll ask to walk slowly. You’ll ask to talk with your friends. They will keep by your side. You’ll ask to be alone. They will show you to a place where you can be alone. You will negotiate with one only to be passed off to another, who claims to be different from the first, who is bringing you to a different place than the first. You will meet one after another, each with his own charm, his own grasp on English, his own care for your needs, his own empathy. But they’ve all watched the same documentary on the Chicago Police Department, and they all glimmer with the same praise: “Tu es un vrai ami.”</p><p>Here’s what you’ll do. You’ll be speaking French for 20 minutes now to 5 different men who all want to be your guide to the market, who want to sell you nothing and just show you a shop, a shop with clothes made by the community where you will not be supporting the Chinese knock-offs on the streets. You’ll be fine, because such situations are fine for you. But your friends, who are not speaking French, will be frustrated. This is understandable. Your rapport with your salesmen will be tested by your constant codeswitching to try and communicate the situation, as well as your plan, to those following you. And then you’ll perform. Then you’ll perform the frustrated American, the one who must be rid of all of these men bombarding him, who make him anxious, who just wants to be alone and walk around the market unbothered, thinking in English and not lying in French. But then they’ll believe you. Your friends and your salesmen. And the code will switch. Suddenly, your friends will give in, allowing the salesmen to take them away, but the salesmen will give up, deciding to leave you alone. The two are incommensurable.</p><p>And here’s a man. A Senegalese man who has watched your performance. He has read your anger and knows how to cut to your core. He will stand up, dressed in subdued colors that render him a prophet, not a shyster. He will speak fluent English. He will accuse you of being insensitive. He will say, “This is how it is done in African markets. They are not being rude. They are not hassling you. They will not make you buy anything that you don’t want to buy.” They are being rude. They are hassling you. They will make you buy things that you won’t want to buy.</p><p>You will give up.</p><p>And you will ascend. You will ascend through a crowd hustlers licking their lips. You will fly past the peddlers, your guides parting the sea of swindlers and shoppers. Up three flights of stairs you will arrive in a shop of endless bright colors and magical fabrics that are stacked miles high. You will swim in a pool of hand-painted magnets. You will dance with the drums made fresh from skinned lambs. You will sport the fabrics of ancient imams. But this is not the open air market. You cannot walk away. You will see them, all the familiar faces. The many swindlers have trapped you here. The sharks are circling the minnows. The ones you spoke with, successfully ignored, will scowl at their missed meals, while those who never took to the streets will try to snatch up the ones who have lost a guide. They’re all here, swarming. They will separate you into different rooms and tell you different prices. You will make many excuses. You will bargain at your best. But they know what you’re actually paying for: you’re paying to be left alone.</p><p>You will buy an overpriced shirt that is racially insensitive.</p><p>Picture not included.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Sandaga Market, the sharks eat the minnows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the sun, setting over flat, low roofs. People 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>I Know Where the Missing Socks Go</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/10/I-Know-Where-the-Missing-Socks-Go/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/10/I-Know-Where-the-Missing-Socks-Go/</id>
    <published>2020-01-10T18:22:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-10T18:28:17.097Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>I know where the missing socks go. I know because I’ve found them. When you load your socks, wet and crumpled and inside-out, into the metal drum that whirs and winds with the afternoon chores, the heat is not there to warm them. The spin does not untangle them. The minutes, counting down, do not track the time until they are dry as a bone, shrunk and ready to stretch. It tracks the time until they return.</p><p>When you load your socks, they are fired off to the homes of Dakar, where they are wrapped together in a towel bindle. Then, a maid quietly brings them up to the roof, where she fills three buckets: one nearly full of suds and bubbles, another half-full and flat, and final bucket completely empty. With a forceful arm, she grabs the socks one by one, dunking them into the suds and pulling them up for air, only to squeeze and stretch and wrestle their limp fabric until they are drowned once again. After a good scrubbing, they are tossed into the second bucket to rest, se reposer, until they are grabbed by the half-dozen, then strung together like unwound strings, and wrung until they won’t give up any more water. Fine, they will give the rest to the sun and the stiff oceanic wind, filled with dust and salt, as they make tiny sails along the clothesline. But one will decide, filled with hatred for all of mankind, that it’s time to escape this endless (rinse) cycle. It will loosen itself from the pin’s grasp and let fly into the rooftops, bouncing off walls and windows until it disappears into the setting winter sun, free at last. You will watch with an unsurprised grimace as the maid chuckles at your misfortune.</p><p>You will also try, as it will become your weekly task, to replicate her motions, but your gentle hands will only tickle the socks, your forceful wrung will keep them moist, and your overzealous armful of pins and socks will surely send more of them into the air. At this, she will laugh the whole time.</p><p>At home, you will open the drum and pull out all of your socks, except for one. You will lose your sock and buy another, tossing the unmatched pair into the garbage or converting it into a dust rag or accepting that you’ll never have the right length of fabric on both ankles. You will do this many times. You will stop loading dishes in the sink and start filling every rack of the dishwasher with even the most gently used cups of water. You will look up words on your phone as the dictionaries gather dust, and you will handwrite letters only when the opportunity arises, once again searching how to write a cursive “G.” You will reread the rules of board games on the nights that the power goes out, and you’ll ask the candles if they could simply light themselves. You will press “start” on a microwave meal and ask what people used to do before technology. You will forget the names of streets in your neighborhood and become familiar only with the clear blue line that guides you to work and friends and school. Your world will become smaller, a series of connected dots, and the world beyond your window no more a map than a collection of addresses saved by search history. Entire swaths of land will be erased by movies on the backs of airplane headrests, and the bird’s eye view will start to fly blind. You will land in a new city and remember the dot that was your home. You will think of your friends but forget their movements, the tenor of their laughs, the outfits that they never wore on nights out. Instead you will have still images, fractions of the whole.</p><p>You’ll find yourself in a new climate and decide to buy new socks. You’ll put the old ones in a box with other unused clothes. They will go unsold at Goodwill and be sent all around the world. 5 years later, you’ll decide that you want to add another point and line to your map, and you will take that trip to that city on the coast in that massive continent everyone says is the next big thing. You’ll meet a man on a fishing dock who speaks no English and has no fondness for the US wearing a dusty “Hard Rock Cafe” baseball cap and two socks: one that doesn’t match the other.</p><p>Your lost socks are in Dakar, and no, I’m not going to bring them back.</p><p><em>This post is dedicated to the alleyway behind our apartment in Chicago. When we take out the trash, we have to quickly open the gate to the dumpsters and then throw away the bag before the gate closes in order to avoid getting locked out. Once, I threw away a bag and a big mess of tin foil, shaped exactly like the food it housed, escaped the bag and flew into the wind. Later, while walking to work, about 2 blocks away and obscured by buildings, that piece of tin foil flew into my back, and I threw it away.</em></p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1DW7wCihdfj0FTyEKJYUvbR8CQpdL9eq8xCeQXdZwHZgcLuNvkyifFqhzQzu-z3rz8llma2RKZ2hAP5MvwIKyAi6ve4VE-AIV0EBkkFLKfcmX4HNn3JS_BU_AOVz8E6qCyOE2zFtoKsbnU4eVvU5Kg8LEd_yqBhqEdB-RovjGkOa4WzdJwiiCvRgiCKv2X3o-ZlgrXonUFrbP4ZibAb0Tamxnc5U-KXOxAkK39iJuD4RGvdvW5Qaaa5nubfMAZgq3CujfCeTGAl56NiYlMcINbxeHVS72Lj89q6nS99e9jQYEvfWv94nl_-B7w1lo57S8RC5W9vamrwIDJefQGdGkQ0qIo8xMnUYkNPV63yGdtMPBHzHMfewVg7X4Re0GeUmi39ooVrixPCfxMys5FAnUSU4J4G1uFnmPuchYqmEQi6KmUz5RyoCuOVC_IwDo0Lp_jPwFYXaUxmPNmCPHSGmI7f5r4QeAgc-4Hqtr3t3_KQw8uuAHGkVc7w9_w9ipuFf022vHyUe0D1v8kCaBozTBcIY2vO1czN7H4Bxx_ejZXfBg7SJ-dwxFC54jmKRUz8i1Yc9RYWAf0tUGOuvqbuCwP7nX2ix8zIkd7LgecEtkk0nEgBkKde0WAu0WmpWtkpH4MRkjrZMCc4QhYwVMPp75m4et1iQtG5zyW7khF5lVEtD7hgnOXVjlWpCnGxm50TIF4jigUMJlNNGhF_Xx5W-76fI77tVsc1_J1wZbVPy5pFhHizb=w1157-h867-no" alt="my clothes, blowing in the wind"></p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/iZNUAhCKRQOXHNkE09g2dKHt6eaS2NY8HXbMhydQqYnWIp3bAKO4iHPsiSpPz5Z4FbAlLI5d2W9hx2DAVfwnrvlv9HJZIYP8atFqX9Jv0LVx0L_vX5GmDkfWy4JPMHa3uK9Q82cFF7ks3hoE_6lRytjkkVJZfZB7OIuoXosP97LeRBWXVPi2ruirpqgJ0OVm7xSSXmBi-d6zW0vTe6i0MqOht0SYT8L3-F6NBkYSrOTeYHnUGUy2ODTC4R4AxMM1Dnty6IrB1P3C-_2oIYLbeTimmWlmHWvkPDWiA1rH4pbij2HPtgZ1Es4jgIfT3Y5d6JdSjsllVrbONxdfyAJWxKWxHzcjKb-ZQTUrKx2YktY33g7w_kyyws0aYXAGS1sUi4DdiCsOJkftRnHrO96r3M-ukZqir86yfY_1dFmCERw7Q63jX2ltCctgcQCZBt8QIruX8skoeVll9mhoVKjmYSdSoKVVbUS7DkiCovdepOtDZAjajQH5ko1GqkwmiAtGUQmfAuvM8owLurEna3w4fzeOiDf94z8JCpLVDyzeeZV3qzE_DMP_wGJ81TfZLTB3M6v-8R-Rw9ztZugLgbH6qmEZHz66gAdA6NXwwA-Ok8q5id9Klw-P0dcZo8iAkjW2ZjX_ZzvZaW8vOHWH_XzMZkdWD2fJzPfr3-0HXSpeY9tcnlaipdMHu2ycz4s_mKby3CkbAaA2hiFDr1TjgK2BVfdNusYHHoxJep9HavPrAx6UPhIO=w1157-h867-no" alt="my socks and undies i guess"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know where the missing socks go. I know because I’ve found them. When you load your socks, wet and crumpl
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Some Necessary Information</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/08/Some-Necessary-Information/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/08/Some-Necessary-Information/</id>
    <published>2020-01-08T21:39:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-10T18:21:11.885Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>We must regroup. We’re in the thick of it; now, for a second, we pull our heads out from underwater. Let me explain where, why, and how we are here.</p><p>We are in Dakar for the next 9 weeks. Dakar is the largest city in Senegal, a West African nation of 16 million. 4 million live in Dakar. It is a Muslim nation, a former French colony, and known as one of the most hospitable places in the world. It is renowned for its markets, poets, and beautiful coastline. Most people speak Wolof, an indigenous language, but many people also speak French. We will be learning Wolof here, and we will also be taking courses on African civilization. C’est tout.</p><p>We came here for a lot of reasons. Namely, our school has a requirement to study civilizations. We decided to do it on-site, where we would not expect to go at any other point in our lives. C’est tout.</p><p>How are we here? We are here as the newly adopted children of a host family. Our mother, Maman, is a seamstress and a woman of infinite kindness. At every meal, sitting around the bowl of food from which we all eat with fork or spoon or piece of bread, she asks about our well-being, she quizzes us on our Wolof, and she demands to know our reviews of her food. She makes beautiful dresses, flashes of colorful beads on long, bright robes that flow with the dusty wind, and the care with which she sits at that sewing machine is replicated in her attention to the details of our impermanent residence. Thread by thread, she adds, renews, and redesigns her home to accommodate our needs, and as she gets to know us, the home does too. More than anyone else, she is our bridge into Dakar. Papa is a quiet man, incredibly polite and intelligent, speaking casually about his international success in journalism and labor organization. On his bookshelf rests towering works of philosophy, history, and linguistics, and yet he has the gall to doubt his near perfect English. Were I lost in Dakar, I’d call him first.</p><p>Our home rests in Sacre-Coeur, a small residential neighborhood outside of the city center. Everyday we take a taxi to the coast to go to our research center where we take classes. The streets are filled with sand, cows roam through marketplaces, and small boutiques pop up at the bottom of apartment buildings. Everywhere you go, a man is wandering around, arms full of SIM cards or bracelets or woven baskets trying to pawn off goods. The air tastes of sand. The showers are cold. The sunsets are short. The days are long. The food is to die for and might very make a Westerner feel like they are dying. C’est tout.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must regroup. We’re in the thick of it; now, for a second, we pull our heads out from underwater. Let me
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Hungry Hound of Dakar: Ceebu jen</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/06/The-Hungry-Hound-of-Dakar-Ceebu-jen/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/06/The-Hungry-Hound-of-Dakar-Ceebu-jen/</id>
    <published>2020-01-06T23:25:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-06T23:36:06.401Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Nick Earley</em></p><p>It is only fitting that the man who does not make any food in our heaven of exposed brick back in Chicago writes the food reviews for our time in Dakar. Nevertheless, I believe I have refined my palate and astutely identified flavor profiles over countless nights of salmon, pesto, rice, lumpia, Nutella fluffer-nutters, and, of course, ambrosia-laden Annie’s Mac&amp;Cheese. I intend to accomplish one thing while I am in Senegal on the hunt for the greatest food that the world will ever taste: to make a concerted and dogged effort to steal Steve Dolinsky’s job. See picture below for his smug, rabid, canine snarl.</p><p><img src="https://encrypted-tbn0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcQocU1a5xSabiVBclGlw1dU18-iSOOf8yaiUa0Yzh-aw8Xg6W15&s" alt="smug, rabid, canine snarl"></p><p>I begin in the Kasse family’s household sitting on the ground with the family in a circle. A plate of ceebu jen (pronounced ch-eh-boo jen), Senegal’s national dish, glistens before us. A hodge-podge of carrots, potatoes, cabbage, cassava, onions, and more delicately caresses a fully cooked grouper, bones and all, presented to us upon a generously comfy bed of jollof rice. I’m no stranger to a plate of ceebu jen. From my hunts at the hallowed Senegalese restaurants in Chicago and a preliminary tasting of what Dakar’s restaurants had to offer in the early days, I can say with certainty that this is the greatest ceebu jen my snout will ever dip itself into. It is glorious. But patience is a cultural touchstone here and the hound in me is tamed down. As is said in Wolof: Ndank ndank mooy japp golo ci naay (slowly, slowly we catch the monkey in the bush). We stay within our little triangular section of the collective plate, respectfully letting the elders toss us meat into our place. I try to make sure I only eat with my right paw as is customary in Senegal but often I forget and then nervously watch to see if anyone else had seen the faux pas. As my belly gets fuller and fuller, I stay alert to announce SURNA SURNA SURNA SURNA at the slightest mention of a LEKKA LEKKA LEKKA but it never comes. For our first meal, the family knows that we are finished and we head back to delve into the deliciously perfect after-meal Senegalse tea known as attaya. But the hound is tired for now. He’ll talk about attaya at another point. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nick Earley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only fitting that the man who does not make any food in our heaven of exposed brick back in Chicago wri
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My Nextdoor Neighbor is a Goat</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/06/My-Nextdoor-Neighbor-is-a-Goat/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/06/My-Nextdoor-Neighbor-is-a-Goat/</id>
    <published>2020-01-06T22:18:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-07T01:00:49.776Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>My name is Malick Kasse. At least, that’s the name assigned to me by my host mother, Maman. She has claimed me as her son, so I have become Malick Kasse. Our host father was given Nick, who is now Papa Kasse, named after his new father (who we call Papa). Like papa like papa.</p><p>For the next two months, I’ll be living on the 5th floor terrace of a tall, narrow apartment building. When the windows are open, red-breasted songbirds perch on my bookshelf until I move too suddenly, sending them back into the heat of the winter sun. I share the terrace with a long clothesline where maids will come to do the family’s laundry, but I share the Dakar roofs with a number of neighbors. Large satellite dishes and radio towers scour the sky, birds of prey and various gulls circle the streets below, and just outside my window a goat watches his owner wash clothes from a rooftop pen, baaing when the spirit moves him. Two smaller goats keep their distance. Today, I called to him in French, but he did not respond. Tomorrow, I will try Wolof.</p><p>Nick lives in a smaller room on the second floor. He didn’t lose the coin toss, he lost the “I can speak French” toss. Papa has strong English, as does his daughter, but Maman only speaks French. Their home is lovely, which makes sense because it houses lovely people. They are immediately welcoming, communal, and kind. At every turn, our compliments are questioned: “You really like the house?”, “You think this is beautiful?”, “You don’t have to eat it if you don’t like it.” But it’s all true, and more than that, it’s inexpressible how true it is. There are no words—in Wolof, French, English, or elsewhere—that demonstrate the gratitude and appreciation we have for a home that is gorgeous, food that is delicious, and hosts who are so kind. Our only complaint is how paranoid we are of offending them.</p><p>To delay offense, we gave them a lot of gifts. Notebooks, mint chocolates, a snow globe, and, best of all, a large, gaudy blanket decorated with a montage of Obama’s startling patriotism, his proud, stern expression looking far into the distance. Perhaps he knew where he would one day end up. Maman and Papa flipped, but I’m not sure if it will ever be hung up as promised. If it is, I’ll make sure to send pictures.</p><p>On the subject of food, I’m dying. When we came home for dinner, Maman said that she would prepare us something small. I ate more than I would on Thanksgiving. I ate until I was full, and then I ate three times that. The plan is to abandon clothes in Senegal when I leave. If I keep eating like this, I might have no other choice.</p><p>It’s hard to separate the beauty of the city from its immense poverty. While there are homes like ours, populated with hard-working laborers, even the most well-off do a disproportionate amount of work for the amount of money that they receive. We can glamorize their trades and rationalize their quality of life in comparison to the less fortunate, but the fact remains that life is hard. And for the people on the street, the children running barefoot from car to car, skinny as skeletons, it is difficult to turn a blind eye. The presidential palace is buffered by slums on either side, and tourists walk through tin huts to go to luxurious beaches. Seaside slums are lobbed effortlessly down cliffside by French construction companies, tossing debris into the ocean and turning homeless camps into collections of dust and garbage. The hotels of wealthy tourists, the embassies of foreign governments, and the homes of Dakar’s few ultra-rich and politicians share sidewalks with mounds of trash, share beaches with destitute peddlers, and share the sky with plumes of smog and dust. Wealth cannot change the air one breathes: it is dust all the same. In Dakar, a society built on sharing must also share pain.</p><p>Today we toured the city with a guide whose bitterness towards colonization was integrated into his explanations of history. Sixty years after independence, the French influence makes citizens furious, yet the apathy for a foreign government that takes so much and gives so little is strong: but what is Dakar without France? According to him, colonization is alive and well, just with a new skin.</p><p>On a lighter note, we went to the beach. The taxi ride back was a mixture of terror and amusement. When we weren’t going 90kmh, we were breaking 90 laws a minute. Sidewalks became shortcuts, one-ways all-ways, and medians mere annoyances, still nothing to prevent our driver from crossing a 6 lane road like he was playing Frogger. Taxis here are a staple of transit for citizens, and for tourists a necessity. If I could take anything from the Senegalese traffic system, it’d be the polite honks directed at drivers in the left lane going too slow. In America, we’d never allow for polite honks.</p><p>Here’s where photos of my room will go. The sun was so bright that I couldn’t even look out the viewfinder. A bientot.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/25MAsZlSG_hvGs_uDNQd2GBZ1pqw1r9segYtl68p7DY3VH0i9P7bbSBLbrAAKEgSzEQ3AymkSOaj-cquNiwQwuIAoV8z1O6WscBkH6vNDS5UlmncwBhHgbF5J1lqcdaPDIisslF2bel2aD6MmoI-gnQosDeLKDJKAWEQJLf61xFz015yH2koYEH59hnX7SaYCcNHi3_8IIp_iL4hh7ThNihwrUMr6yLHGBF-H6SdKQlHkGkmlOgbXwL3g8vo2ArZn7XH7uOGeVpf2GFEiE5uqc-K5DtRXsVP0myAo2aHDZM43nRAhGAtYpFpJhLINkMiz-XZw4Eyegv5fULhqII5OsXy92ASyP2-xfeaTfDmqnz0T18AADNmiG3FzjGMmwFq2_5R2-B-TTyUWbCyLAj8A0C4w-TiSGCF2ukD6vOlC-krmDI4MpORtrtDN36V7xKVd4iNJLVddBXjUUZ3Cm2pQjQ0vDwnQo0FM_3KYbgq5k8hKiVHlILGPt9NCvUtqhk6_FdMtqBr2XKNwSQjiwZD7Q9gqLXURkvOstQ87qnj1DY3Pp1OIlXvEGSe1nQWEY1GIhgnfQ5l_GMD5YQMkFSoU4g3k9StEu9WrHw53PIwsujehN8qbHm8YfnlObE7A9A-2aPZT_0MGYkT95q4ogn4jhJ3GpLyeNMDcljeeguiS_uMaL-2ANDXGqWw8XfZUMEGNQlsTjCbvQbiawLxfdB3Amv56lxvBCzd3dIyBo4senrs66o7=w1157-h867-no" alt="my goat neighbor"><br><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/RCswilS0aLqWRuniJmuBAj9bs7qrNXAYSOFvaKTZzr1ldyrCxVo5ZLzhOZGYjf3brYz22dQL0lyP1xqgwtQn3YDuu4ofuyzI8OjkyeVwhXjnQfUmqZgBs_MWY1KVXtFw5WYV3qSF7LcKkRs2UTkSmLLwxBsfp8utTPvf8rbfriiT_cv1nmI898-FtW2L_TvAvcclZu5DPZTRWJqs8FeStuSvN_rr_lNlAugj1k69TXF8KegumhUYIYmqwz0mB3DdoHwmBDZMn5aeSNEkzwIHdt9bDQRDOCu224x3N2PCHbaiSAupo_1J8fTemdIiHwVQcNrmQfeNJYKlWfkVEUBx-Sc5j1WJGm9ewfvx-YKjXQ6FxG2G4O9nMwJ1Uy1PBG-bDfYvFpEXT-ClMFp3lM1ni1lhHk7Qqsz9WZpg24mzCOAJV6cZ4fzeArBPoyWpbFfyOmTEZ995lhkdeFYXgxZeGMsnzsr2z8u6E4GORjpkTtp3KVe6sOWoKFyiSfnTSzSoloyF7XvjPXTSa6QcdywiRPB64N3fWuBWkbovZUjkg92xYZkWCig5rrQekcj8z5aIWu05A1V2noo07nuJ-EVSKVOc0GxB5Q86Tz9JwZPBQuqNY18gv325-Yea9HvMQvzy-4c3W0szjC4cQoa4t-zDz-M8utWidptJaBrPHGBnXTnQyeff4BNhZED7YdSY4r83RE9uHZ5uTRRNx9LlIhBUlmqLwBqtZjmKdIhAFbVFS9hqByJU=w1157-h867-no" alt="a radio tower"><br><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/0R1-k1AYxPujySMOBK5UywodKWOMnPL4wvVRnH5OZ4gMus1OkPr8MGSJ-yCcKAITwEZ9PQh4APkYKA65CZE1cXDCB_LYLMYq2vB690Pc9jRQ21FtJ14o0BFCyHQ7R8NaYldIzu9txrh9Gt8CBXIhGN_pf9MDwwTHJctfLyPDN0z___IqqeQ5JR41nzitJEsvFJxcIzYKkfDhZWpW3CoOJRCcApAZIkJyAnuUovLiuNvVOt68_CpvWPsCPmjFLFkV9Tb97RFBhEdmrQ5u4_Zcpzvi8RtDoa20_GT2HjvFAFQxkuckeBH0Gdn8SNhElk1b4_O5UasLfsyi0JPLnqawg0tJPnswcgrBH1Zr9aTK5AZWwjMVmTHbP5wmU3mPrBkBhY0JrzYaaTFj_y-S3C7IMCbw5b3_1bEhQ17SNr7srvmZqn33X-MODGMqldTFgaDk9TWLd-4Lj-5AbbxVbgSfAiTmz_pfPzozyFg-PUefPSYDTlASsw3ftKHLYHI_kxo9todFVaaPCKmv4WwHvO1YQHWGGYd4KLciH-lp3PsAJ-vt2Qr6kMHkaXTjvOZUmrkqTfZMkBxeT5bZ-lTYaT9mW8UQKd5vq-euVaKUNW-9zEutK-t0j_9GYx6UmHOzXNsycJeTBd9akbUKKlq3j_E4KJXjq0-e7im_TYDULRTU9WU-I6jepBHzIT7HGRdODeEbq12lX5BP0cQVupM_7EiAIX_cog0XSO6iqhEKDfoTnLSj2pvv=w1157-h867-no" alt="the city and open sky"><br><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/KBbyBhXadjSJNN6-GH3KiPRcY60axnFW6DnM6oZhEOtg5Zo_c9KVB9-VnJWEQeHf-ffyORvv7V4hSs4n16mMrQ4jEeUNFxyJdzyRbEPfN1vtulzrSQtlsUBt4a00xHCehIUCEGf0sd0FDmeNw4rsLj3ExnS9O08Wmcr-NDTlUNJLf1gQNfQpdhMMSQKKcARIYivGKBI_ePU1KdYwNI3UwP8wN9EcbQOSr5ExTU8l7higq5L3wHR7IV7rt_VsXA3gQB2dD211Kf3x5t9phCsP60Kqm6hedrFPkZvn3i2Q2ajN8LwToI_TfUlzl5MSS0m4BwMZy9M15gLbHyJPSbRmBBc-7obvRW6RdgH1_JTqmRDsRbUvrgxJ9rAH-IrNzAGaRtRlHduy4dg20tiIAlVy4WmzDVLVEGf8kUj0hyPpIVnO7ytcxfDGf7JRxPi9jcwabtWk6DG0YOfKzMeSWc4SuY98M3blKJ7E01V2fka0Cg2JvYbXPZd_8osya5yjoeR15vuuevte8d7axm5Es0XjwL6X4jbp1uv6GGGYfTz0-SaRWhGJmcOkR8xpt_AQuFAPIDOgG13gEq7M7uU_0MtJm3xSVe9c3lac3-ES55PHSflHLWggCtWe3C2WLgWmZ-ZXsp9ez6RppFQ1h_28CBHaa1V3oUJVD6eNL72mSOpx9Le5JLvhKmQyTgI-DZtvdW58x2Yl9Jmh-duMcO-LsCZJiz_adMipbSlTd9nU3drzbwjSz8lx=w1157-h867-no" alt="a pink home"><br><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/eRmK-BorggJe7o0M89Ef_eAm2S3rolEr5AEv4XmfNZ8vqeiWnfvUcegcj0QB3nFu4NLOGlWKvZgnjUJesJM1Tg-w0Ysrgg8AwaL8s7O6PYFF6K_1cET50SrXYQLC39rgkaoWDYZ_a8yNAKXYV-rxOynjBXv9_XGegUSwXrEbpc7HycOpjYO09_mivasMzYJ5HW1mPX1oVlY6PWrAHx2urRpPP1m5AoI8uHScVfglGhbOz9h9G8Mrj0FiAh-PqOs9To-Kzig3ldb6D9VvI_2nHGsGm0N6KIQMLLsAPmCfryqoHsO7G9brp0JcKcG3SlbjKbJARZ8sPKDRPGCYuBR9fQ41fCklgHW_Il4Y9iwVxA16TI5w8ysrgcU0K8qo0RPlK05mHtDcUBkdYGDxOu1SaNcu_dwmfPjHH2EQ5b4hXVbtwGBbeae4SRxT-7SteUidi7Q7tLYYoeZfxshvtwjo8HLrH1orpqTR2JvvuPEWvSMmGk8QWebBMEc7gbO-t2twRNNP_kV6fEAERbhhEXH5Gk4WxM0cHpormcIkFrfZdlsQbymn71zht8IZq1tyLVa3AcxSQZQ2ksE2s_LRGxMzz0oGXH_OFO6iAp6MDx6C8uucvwVZiWBReXudAGaz3-sJ6An0ohwJudGom31vQZuS_6jdah9RBkZUnRM0yrjk9G1PU4SoGAeAaIyyb1AE1y4OxFgCkQQOw44NLAwRtD-HemXunqSinyt640Npm0w0RgxR3ooZ=w1157-h867-no" alt="a white home"><br><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Me8BkbA2xI12WlzaTfM8viSI4FSSEVkgLonqZK0BJ933k3BNQBCTgdwazMcdv87u17ReNXu7sW8HmnonzyCfDoouvSBSWNdok3HF8MZVK1BOEoOxN0fI33xCJr8TEckZtW0fOCwyePAYmxVdDRYR6bBrf9XIWAbQUYnxc32oYtsdQ5INGr800aLY8FoMo0CgxWiCxwdLghRlCk9hxj2nPl6K9wkgEURo8cW-t4qeXBGwpzNBIddTfeDfteRNiRIoTEsRNhrLXPL7os7pq9E-gH525OBbxB-xhbM6uHyPFPMGaSCVk74PfVWE2XwGwj8bILiU79sR9PKnAmKUhwtveXL1_algtwU5dfv5fyzIAcMx7L6m8Ibdw0nIEd4RC2-ztRudJfh6JgGQinTtqRId99xLlR6fpTt8SWN8XOedvg3ftgUsCDPTVFZiz0NxoPVlStiNZ8Hcs9YdqZ9vwvW3F4rrULlJBt49LuMSAteJ_jUtwZXJLFA-kiWvNZb8_LpWZrnyjNb3mlDiTRag78rHt6EHI1TGo4TMGQKgsSUiT1LzELFUZugKGmmRmBjndgEPH5d04pmxYuVlTw4fFiKxqUGuoovbuFQ06HpkFSeQ-jgQAy7khXRW-HvfEDA_PDageHUL3zDrJhw2yYtdMTZlZxIt4ZqTFqzrZenCFwAQL0_8F8SZ9TKZR9lI0QDKaNtDQIGFkMeGN0G4FAPwe4uWPdun3ni6PB22cpmRC_j4zAO3sKKk=w1157-h867-no" alt="the street below"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Malick Kasse. At least, that’s the name assigned to me by my host mother, Maman. She has claimed
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Longest Conversation I&#39;ve Had in French Was with a Dog</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/04/The-Longest-Conversation-I-ve-Had-in-French-Was-with-a-Dog/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/04/The-Longest-Conversation-I-ve-Had-in-French-Was-with-a-Dog/</id>
    <published>2020-01-05T04:26:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-06T23:39:02.670Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>81 degrees and the dust is in my lungs. Today we bought SIM cards and people tend to follow my lead. We’ll see if this proves to be a bad habit.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/aMfXy6YbtQIM4YtNvfEAM8SjAIxARMvWgcnL5-Er18OtDeucZ-kPaXuFvTfb13jTMCnwr45BXsd2nvjkzIHvawcKYRhqmxyqyEnqupifhsKAdAze-j-gaXfw7Z135iNl1-YlBItD3eKYbLcsrZaofcC62ywKjWsq-1IoN6RNT2j8M8WoBI9Fm4r5pHKfZWZMtjsVO6s0qli7aW8h1ttv-UEGPKFl3Ww4GUUBl8OSLmW801F20mWxWVyOHMD6onYeKhCl4ZFZ28TGJ3qgy4C3YXxKSnGDtmhgrHqvZcp8IT0y-nP0Nl8viMiQIgJ1Wn67BJcb7xwxNQBaWAms7Zdnea0koen_V0TO1m1ToxJ_oAmoGu2WuYQK4GkCaNsIPxe4efmAX8M5MNLZX196JyoSA2Fxx7e1cIBKcHkYpHhqdiOC6STZkeWYonrm2W3TSJBMEnFvu9j21LcDIvD5zse3LdG_FlZDsDSTulGZjRXxiJswctxT4f03cm9muNRHGEGDhQH7gwvSlr_gJgpj9vCFyDS_HbKlGIIboPyQR9vIczl2MGiOzy8q70Y_AdkioqyYRxwAnedO320fw55mCEJutGqWqbzjlbf-M2Y-AqiynWl7NgAy2bE5SUbvMrI7_s8HklgCnpcMGDvL7PYImGqIZMHyLtJROzdijUT6T5Nc48KiWf7LRbr32uTFTu6PxKCdk74SirMEu_a8yeu2w9J8CGV5796xIxsPH7cWpQ8ctQx01GZ8=w1157-h867-no" alt="a cathedral"></p><p>In a pet store, a small dog raced around my feet. He lost interest and ran after Nick, who responded by running out of the store. Luring him back inside with tasty suede shoes, he bit at my shoelaces until he was dragged to the shop floor, where I said phrases like “Tu aimes le pantalon” and “Tu es mignon mais je dois partir.” Eventually he jumped at my knee and, catching fabric with his teeth, hung on my leg, hind legs off the ground, until the pet store owner pulled him away.</p><p>It’s this confidence with dogs that landed me at the head of every little excursion, first out to get more SIM cards and then to the ocean. We passed the Presidential Palace where a terse security guard informed me that photographs were forbidden, and we then skirted through a row of embassies until we landed on a winding cliffside road overlooking the water. As people took photos on DSLRs, Nick snapped a few shots on his disposable Kodak camera, which I had gifted to him like a mother might give a child a small vacuum cleaner that consists solely of pinwheels and plastic balls. The line between the grey, still ocean and the grey, still sky was obscured by the clouds of dust.</p><p>We hiked farther down the road to a soccer field, where a mini detour through some bramble and paths made of buried tires once again called into question my leadership role. By the time we made it back to the hotel, the collective exhaustion rendered us silent. Again, they really should not be putting their faith in me, despite my laughable knowledge of French, ability to use Google Maps, and maternal energy.</p><p>They did it again and a few hours later we were heading to a marketplace in search of toilet paper and food. We ran into Alouine, a street salesman who had tried to lead us to a textile outlet the day before. Today, we became fast friends, and he helped us find toilet paper as well as a restaurant on the condition that we visit his textile outlet. This was a mistake. The outlet was filled with peddlers more persistent than Alouine, but with a few francs he got the idea that his friends should leave us alone. Faith in me was, regretfully, restored.</p><p>There are no streetlamps. Headlights barely manage to punctuate the heavy air. Housecats are thin and stray sare thinner. Men wear empty jugs of water on their backs like porcupines wear quills, dozens at a time. Word of advice, just say “non, merci.”</p><p>These probably won’t be daily. I need to work on my prose.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/teLMP8K3tW4ZGgZOm5gqK5UIP_4DBgNNTK4wcHuVEolJiGc-eO8Y7OubCVOcPa73BHr9max2g40IU0OVqX-ppHpRY1N2VnudvuaRBdpP8Uf84deQ_iMkB4sFJcRkPDnWlbYChESJ-E_GEJo3WCbVs5Xhx4nNR9SJ67JB1n7YNM6YTvsGDy8RfYhI5DCi0XvpNClOOPCBFgBzcfNjhZbVdxsH-DTIg7Quk_WwiyTJLP8ZewLO9erFb8eRGKRw6qnqzQrHyZBK08W2RxA4tY-F8DMP8qffXOoeKhxuYcES2qbcMtkGiu38NaeD8V6Du0SCPH6_IibPKf-aFT5UehTq0ESR7sshUbhzcW9gJVI7HS-vTZYyR1R4DsJwgACHOJNL6uLn6iplM2yw1sKmK43mG9UyGqQsxT7qTyPfAQ-BMBeNL0En2d6HmSatQxgz1WDg9EbDaN9k_PAwFYKhTlSAjXiIwuK4AnqT9MEq2wZR1S1dJ7HlXy_se4MXV_EkqHbr6PPOvMh071nKIbaTerU8lmoASvnYz91kj38Azs2ZbCtUWq3z6uyVsoQI-Z_uhgveFThoPBP7HGNup7WnZBGIkQ75QTRRiEHvo3VLQQCbiWYprOvif0n2TMclwJ4NLz2K8nlzZiL9y2WzMRED0Ld5T_H35M2y9nKwdWXHVk-447kzHol69PC3JnIArtzJpi495PjFHlIH5TjsDdpwQiLVnOHtfzqoAXBTXeKlMTYvBDPW5KZ_=w1337-h867-no" alt="a big old building"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;81 degrees and the dust is in my lungs. Today we bought SIM cards and people tend to follow my lead. We’ll 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>When the Night Falls Down</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/03/When-the-Night-Falls-Down/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/03/When-the-Night-Falls-Down/</id>
    <published>2020-01-04T04:06:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-06T23:40:26.674Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>I saw the stars from the plane, gliding over the quiet Atlantic Ocean in the dead of night. As we pulled into Lisbon, the streetlamps flickered into distinct specks of life scattered across the dark cityscape, mirroring their celestial counterparts and attempting to render Belinda Carlisle’s refrain true. Threading the needle between two heavens, my underwater ears interpreted the background murmur as the conversations of people on the ground, a city spoke into life.</p><p>There’s not much of interest from the first two legs of our journey (Boston &amp; Lisbon), save an eavesdropped exchange between a father and daughter and a Portuguese orange juicer, both replicated here:</p><p>Toddler daughter: “Dad can we get my bag from the merry-go-round?”<br>Dad: “No because it’s called a bag carousel but it’s very funny that you are calling it that.”<br>Daughter: “I’m funny dad?”<br>Dad: “Yes.”<br>Daughter: “How did I do that?”</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qly3am2gKu6wwj16kslKUNoHB0XlvfLr0J3Qt2P_FgczWe8gvtSlPkF5ElzN4nhf_z5ARkXZnpMT5T2EnoQ7oRQKISwITpYF-sdbUY7bb9sJyXupIIcOXIiLz5dsqKA3S7vnYMgULVbHX6KLy7j5JI8-o5yefaqvBoRzWhExgN5gUiGkR9vEIj4LqaOW3QfhWQitBL0p-RwZKMbkQZgwfHKfPqcYbN9k_8_PCIhb3N31ZpdALXZSLSjMGOT7-L_PwM2PgoHtbf346awoRGKSrK_FkhEBusJ-jBakHnjvH8ijkUwcCok25fBR5j-VebP912UZ02idtm_-bMgt8d8xX2kFbhZp3NhnT73115Va-ED9VP3cZC7hxOu48NlbZn_3qC7mFFNONiD7Q8zkNjaz57S2e--gpKdz01wVf7uMuoguao4RMP6IplbmCgWYdjwXRLPfDa0nHl6OYjIonE5RghdaeTKibR5RXS4niXwZ_OqlVrvJ5DFM58a1TBLOIoygBOoK2WiJCOJ4IBXFTrsKNK0VVrpL3yWtavMqmBdDtadgAVWivoiZaOXo8EgV2wl0cUmxpaO9I4_3NsEPUldZrbT_w_4N1_R3mCHd_fjXdMsmkjgKhoURTKRvotKojEfK0Oelv7D_ynUeufbwgHiky2GNbmx_i7codZTm2p7pZ9W2SDb96CyUlkCxpjFcSsTvQiK8j74_qS5yuxWkH7XmuAqGIMOnUUViqSOfbI-3JuwW732u=w945-h867-no" alt="poorly drawn juice machine"></p><p>The forecast for Dakar was 81 degrees with “widespread dust.” The dry air felt cooler, and what appeared to be distant fog was instead dust whipped up into the horizon, blocking out the sun. We were picked up at the airport, the eight of us that coincidentally ended upon the same flight, and driven to a hotel by a representative of the program.</p><p>Our motley crew had been slowly spun together as flights aligned and we reached new destinations, recognizing each other as members of the same program. Overheard conversations, college merch, and awkward eye contact from orientation meetings landed us in that van together.</p><p>In the trek from the rural airport to the city, a Martian landscape of blood orange soil unfolded, signs of life cropping up with towering baobab trees and little palms that punctuated the flat earth. Deer crossings were replaced with signs for monkey crossings and habitats. As we cruised down the wide barren road at an easy 120kmh, a collective whiplash turned our heads to the thud behind us. One of the bags which were, unbeknownst to us, simply placed on top of the van, had flown off the roof and skidded across the pavement where a cab driver pulled over to remove the hazard. With the addition of some rope, which we apparently had all along, we were up and running again.</p><p>The luggage was unharmed.</p><p>As we got closer to the urban center, signs of suburbs manifested in half complete cinderblock towns, often roofless or unpainted, and populated with construction workers overturning more of the red soil. Eventually, full towns took shape, and people wandered about on rooftops and played soccer in the fields of red dirt. Clotheslines were suspended across terraces, where entire living rooms might appear in the winter sun, couches left on the roof with no fear of rain. The dust was widespread.</p><p>Everyone seems to own the same large white van, with purposes varying to taxiing groups around the city to operating as a spectre of public transit, people hopping aboard when the opportunity arose or hanging from the side ladder when the space overflowed. Meanwhile, men stacked massive pallets of goods to the trunks of miniscule 2-wheeled carts pulled by solo horses. With trash overflowing beyond cinderblock walls, and fields of dust turning into apartment buildings, we realized that we were finally in Dakar.</p><p>The homes, mostly white plastered concrete buildings with colorful accent around archways and open terraces, reflected not only historical African styles, but also designs at home in the Arab world. Along the sidewalks, if you’re so inclined to call them sidewalks, dozens of people laid down prayer mats and knelt together. Taxi drivers pulled over for afternoon prayers. But just as quickly as we encountered a devout Muslim population, we were met with Christmas decorations and a large, lavish cathedral. Dakar is a place of sharing. People are offended if you do not share greetings. People are disturbed by the isolation of visibly armed civilians, who number very few. And people do not understand the separation of religious rituals and holidays. The world is shared by the people within it, so why practice any act of distancing?</p><p>The city looks older in part due to its mistreatment. Plaster falls off homes, vines overtake facades, and half-finished construction projects leave massive holes in the ground with accompanying mounds of dirt. But while people make benches out of giant, useless concrete slabs and empty fruit boxes, they plug in airpods and sport new clothes, an anachronism of wealth.</p><p>I’m too tired to read this over, but I’m sure you get the gist of the city. We’re staying in a hotel for the night, but Sunday we’ll make out way to our host families.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the stars from the plane, gliding over the quiet Atlantic Ocean in the dead of night. As we pulled in
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How Big is a Home?</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/28/How-Big-is-a-Home/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/28/How-Big-is-a-Home/</id>
    <published>2019-12-29T02:09:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-06T23:31:46.560Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>Nick is standing 181 inches across from me in our 2 bedroom apartment that we’ve occupied for the last 6 months. We know the question that anyone who knows us is asking: <em>what’s happening to the brick?</em> Over the past few days we’ve packed up our winter gear, sent our intergalactic friend Yubba to the care of another home, and removed the plants from the windowsill. Our little apartment, with its quaint exposed brick, is being left behind.</p><p>We’ve found two subletters, a cheerful German man studying music and a kind Italian doctor. We think we’ve left the place in good hands, but we will miss Woodlawn while we’re in Senegal.</p><p>Tonight, we’re heading to Chinatown to find gifts for the residents of our new home in Dakar. We have no idea what to get them. Hopefully, they will never read this blog. If you have any idea what a 31 year old Senegalese woman might like as a housewarming gift, please write us.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick is standing 181 inches across from me in our 2 bedroom apartment that we’ve occupied for the last 6 mo
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome!</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/27/Welcome/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/27/Welcome/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T08:37:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-27T10:20:20.355Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="This-is-our-website"><a href="#This-is-our-website" class="headerlink" title="This is our website"></a>This is our website</h1><p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>We have decided to document our time in Senegal with a blog. We know it’s been done before, by people who are smarter and better than us, but I spent a lot of time programming this site to look nice using hexo.js, GitHub, and Markdown, and I need to get something out of it. We don’t know what we’ll post about here. Probably just food Nick likes, poems I find, and…well…I tried to think of a third thing but honestly that’s about it.</p><p>I don’t know how to code well. So don’t expect too much. Nick will probably ask me to put in something ridiculous, like animated chihuahua that barks out “NICK” when you click it. I can’t do that. I’m only human. And I’m majoring in sociology. Anyways, if there’s something you’d particularly like to see on this blog, just send us a message. I’m sure you know how to contact one of us.</p><p>This post?</p><h2 id="It’s-mostly-just-a-way-to-test-Markdown"><a href="#It’s-mostly-just-a-way-to-test-Markdown" class="headerlink" title="It’s mostly just a way to test Markdown"></a>It’s mostly just a way to test Markdown</h2><p>Actually, I’m writing it at <strong>four AM</strong> because I want it to go live before we leave on a plane. We haven’t even decided on a URL. I don’t know how it looks on mobile. See you in the next one. Placeholder text.</p><p>If you find any out of place Chinese text please let me know. It’s a process.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;This-is-our-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#This-is-our-website&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;This is our website&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is our website&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;e
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
