<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Peter &amp; Nick</title>
  
  <subtitle>Keeping Up With Dakardashians</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-01-04T22:50:57.191Z</updated>
  <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Peter Forberg &amp; Nicholas Earley</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Longest Conversation I&#39;ve Had in French Was with a Dog</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/04/The-Longest-Conversation-I-ve-Had-in-French-Was-with-a-Dog/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/04/The-Longest-Conversation-I-ve-Had-in-French-Was-with-a-Dog/</id>
    <published>2020-01-05T04:26:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-04T22:50:57.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>81 degrees and the dust is in my lungs. Today we bought SIM cards and people tend to follow my lead. We’ll see if this proves to be a bad habit.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/aMfXy6YbtQIM4YtNvfEAM8SjAIxARMvWgcnL5-Er18OtDeucZ-kPaXuFvTfb13jTMCnwr45BXsd2nvjkzIHvawcKYRhqmxyqyEnqupifhsKAdAze-j-gaXfw7Z135iNl1-YlBItD3eKYbLcsrZaofcC62ywKjWsq-1IoN6RNT2j8M8WoBI9Fm4r5pHKfZWZMtjsVO6s0qli7aW8h1ttv-UEGPKFl3Ww4GUUBl8OSLmW801F20mWxWVyOHMD6onYeKhCl4ZFZ28TGJ3qgy4C3YXxKSnGDtmhgrHqvZcp8IT0y-nP0Nl8viMiQIgJ1Wn67BJcb7xwxNQBaWAms7Zdnea0koen_V0TO1m1ToxJ_oAmoGu2WuYQK4GkCaNsIPxe4efmAX8M5MNLZX196JyoSA2Fxx7e1cIBKcHkYpHhqdiOC6STZkeWYonrm2W3TSJBMEnFvu9j21LcDIvD5zse3LdG_FlZDsDSTulGZjRXxiJswctxT4f03cm9muNRHGEGDhQH7gwvSlr_gJgpj9vCFyDS_HbKlGIIboPyQR9vIczl2MGiOzy8q70Y_AdkioqyYRxwAnedO320fw55mCEJutGqWqbzjlbf-M2Y-AqiynWl7NgAy2bE5SUbvMrI7_s8HklgCnpcMGDvL7PYImGqIZMHyLtJROzdijUT6T5Nc48KiWf7LRbr32uTFTu6PxKCdk74SirMEu_a8yeu2w9J8CGV5796xIxsPH7cWpQ8ctQx01GZ8=w1157-h867-no" alt="a cathedral"></p><p>In a pet store, a small dog raced around my feet. He lost interest and ran after Nick, who responded by running out of the store. Luring him back inside with my tasty suede shoes, he bit at my shoelaces until he was dragged back inside, where I said phrases like “Tu aimes le pantalon” and “Tu es mignon mais je dois partir.” He eventually jumped up at my knee and, catching fabric with his teeth, hung on my leg, hind legs off the ground, until the pet store owner pulled him away.</p><p>It’s this confidence with dogs that landed me at the head of every little excursion, first out to get more SIM cards and then to the ocean. We passed the Presidental Palace where a terse security guard informed me that photographs were forbidden, and we then skirted through a row of embassies until we landed on a winding cliffside road overlooking the water. As people took photos on DSLRs, Nick snapped a few shots on his disposable Kodak camera, which I had gifted to him like a mother might give a child a small vacuum cleaner that consists solely of pinwheels and plastic balls. The line between the grey, still ocean and the grey, still sky was obscured by the clouds of dust.</p><p>We hiked farther down the road to a soccer field, where a mini detour through some bramble and paths made of buried tires once again called into question my leadership role. By the time we made it back to the hotel, the collective exhaustion rendered us silent. Again, they really should not be putting their faith in me, despite my laughable knowledge of French, ability to use Google Maps, and maternal energy.</p><p>They did it again and a few hours later we were heading to a marketplace in search of toilet paper and food. We ran into Alouine, a street salesman who had tried to lead us to a textile outlet the day before. Today, we became fast friends, and he helped us find toilet paper as well as a restaurant on the condition that we visit his textile outlet. This was a mistake. The outlet was filled with peddlers more persistent than Alouine, but with a few francs he got the idea that his friends should leave us alone. Faith in me was, regretfully, restored.</p><p>There are no streetlamps. Headlights barely manage to punctuate the heavy air. Even the stray cats are thinner. Men wear empty jugs of water on their backs like porcupines wear quills, dozens at a time. Word of advice, just say “non, merci.”</p><p>These probably won’t be daily. I need to work on my prose.</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/aMfXy6YbtQIM4YtNvfEAM8SjAIxARMvWgcnL5-Er18OtDeucZ-kPaXuFvTfb13jTMCnwr45BXsd2nvjkzIHvawcKYRhqmxyqyEnqupifhsKAdAze-j-gaXfw7Z135iNl1-YlBItD3eKYbLcsrZaofcC62ywKjWsq-1IoN6RNT2j8M8WoBI9Fm4r5pHKfZWZMtjsVO6s0qli7aW8h1ttv-UEGPKFl3Ww4GUUBl8OSLmW801F20mWxWVyOHMD6onYeKhCl4ZFZ28TGJ3qgy4C3YXxKSnGDtmhgrHqvZcp8IT0y-nP0Nl8viMiQIgJ1Wn67BJcb7xwxNQBaWAms7Zdnea0koen_V0TO1m1ToxJ_oAmoGu2WuYQK4GkCaNsIPxe4efmAX8M5MNLZX196JyoSA2Fxx7e1cIBKcHkYpHhqdiOC6STZkeWYonrm2W3TSJBMEnFvu9j21LcDIvD5zse3LdG_FlZDsDSTulGZjRXxiJswctxT4f03cm9muNRHGEGDhQH7gwvSlr_gJgpj9vCFyDS_HbKlGIIboPyQR9vIczl2MGiOzy8q70Y_AdkioqyYRxwAnedO320fw55mCEJutGqWqbzjlbf-M2Y-AqiynWl7NgAy2bE5SUbvMrI7_s8HklgCnpcMGDvL7PYImGqIZMHyLtJROzdijUT6T5Nc48KiWf7LRbr32uTFTu6PxKCdk74SirMEu_a8yeu2w9J8CGV5796xIxsPH7cWpQ8ctQx01GZ8=w1157-h867-no" alt="a big old building"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;81 degrees and the dust is in my lungs. Today we bought SIM cards and people tend to follow my lead. We’ll see if this proves to be a bad
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>When the Night Falls Down</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/03/When-the-Night-Falls-Down/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2020/01/03/When-the-Night-Falls-Down/</id>
    <published>2020-01-04T04:06:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-04T22:26:10.582Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>I saw the stars from the plane, gliding over the quiet Atlantic Ocean in the dead of night. As we pulled into Lisbon, the streetlamps flickered into distinct specks of life scattered across the dark cityscape, mirroring their celestial counterparts and attempting to render Belinda Carlisle’s refrain true. Threading the needle between two heavens, my underwater ears interpreted the background murmur as the conversations of people on the ground, a city spoke into life.</p><p>There’s not much of interest from the first two legs of our journey (Boston &amp; Lisbon), save an eavesdropped exchange between a father and daughter and a Portuguese orange juicer, both replicated here:</p><p>Toddler daughter: “Dad can we get my bag from the merry-go-round?”<br>Dad: “No because it’s called a bag carousel but it’s very funny that you are calling it that.”<br>Daughter: “I’m funny dad?”<br>Dad: “Yes.”<br>Daughter: “How did I do that?”</p><p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qly3am2gKu6wwj16kslKUNoHB0XlvfLr0J3Qt2P_FgczWe8gvtSlPkF5ElzN4nhf_z5ARkXZnpMT5T2EnoQ7oRQKISwITpYF-sdbUY7bb9sJyXupIIcOXIiLz5dsqKA3S7vnYMgULVbHX6KLy7j5JI8-o5yefaqvBoRzWhExgN5gUiGkR9vEIj4LqaOW3QfhWQitBL0p-RwZKMbkQZgwfHKfPqcYbN9k_8_PCIhb3N31ZpdALXZSLSjMGOT7-L_PwM2PgoHtbf346awoRGKSrK_FkhEBusJ-jBakHnjvH8ijkUwcCok25fBR5j-VebP912UZ02idtm_-bMgt8d8xX2kFbhZp3NhnT73115Va-ED9VP3cZC7hxOu48NlbZn_3qC7mFFNONiD7Q8zkNjaz57S2e--gpKdz01wVf7uMuoguao4RMP6IplbmCgWYdjwXRLPfDa0nHl6OYjIonE5RghdaeTKibR5RXS4niXwZ_OqlVrvJ5DFM58a1TBLOIoygBOoK2WiJCOJ4IBXFTrsKNK0VVrpL3yWtavMqmBdDtadgAVWivoiZaOXo8EgV2wl0cUmxpaO9I4_3NsEPUldZrbT_w_4N1_R3mCHd_fjXdMsmkjgKhoURTKRvotKojEfK0Oelv7D_ynUeufbwgHiky2GNbmx_i7codZTm2p7pZ9W2SDb96CyUlkCxpjFcSsTvQiK8j74_qS5yuxWkH7XmuAqGIMOnUUViqSOfbI-3JuwW732u=w945-h867-no" alt="poorly drawn juice machine"></p><p>The forecast for Dakar was 81 degrees with “widespread dust.” The dry air felt cooler, but it’s true that what appeared to be distant fog was instead dust whipped up into the horizon, blocking out the sun. We were picked up at the airport, the eight of us that coincidentally ended upon the same flight, and driven to a hotel by a representative of the program.</p><p>Our motley crew had been slowly spun together as flights aligned and we reached new destinations, recognizing each other as members of the same program. Overheard conversations, college merch, and awkward eye contact from orientation meetings landed us in that van together.</p><p>In the trek from the rural airport to the city, a Martian landscape of blood orange soil unfolded, signs of life cropping up with towering baobab trees and little palms that punctuated the flat earth. Deer crossings were replaced with signs for monkey crossings and habitats. As we cruised down the wide barren road at an easy 120kmh, a collective whiplash turned our heads to the thud behind us. One of the bags which were, unbeknownst to us, simply placed on top of the van, had flown off the roof and skidded across the pavement where a cab driver pulled over to remove the hazard. With the addition of some rope, which we apparently had all along, we were up and running again.</p><p>The luggage was unharmed.</p><p>As we got closer to the urban center, signs of suburbs manifested in half complete cinderblock towns, often roofless or unpainted, and populated with construction workers overturning more of the red soil. Eventually, full towns took shape, and people wandered about on rooftops and played soccer in the fields of red dirt. Clotheslines were suspended across terraces, where entire living rooms might appear in the winter sun, couches left on the roof with no fear of rain. The dust was widespread.</p><p>Everyone seems to own the same large white van, with purposes varying to taxiing groups around the city to operating as a spectre of public transit, people hopping aboard when the opportunity arose or hanging from the side ladder when the space overflowed. Meanwhile, men stacked massive pallets of goods to the trunks of miniscule 2-wheeled carts pulled by solo horses. With trash overflowing beyond cinderblock walls, and fields of dust turning into apartment buildings, we realized that we were finally in Dakar.</p><p>The homes, mostly white plastered concrete buildings with colorful accent around archways and open terraces, reflected not only historical African styles, but also designs at home in the Arab world. Along the sidewalks, if you’re so inclined to call them sidewalks, dozens of people laid down prayer mats and knelt together. Taxi drivers pulled over for afternoon prayers. But just as quickly as we encountered a devout Muslim population, we were met with Christmas decorations and a large, lavish cathedral. Dakar is a place of sharing. People are offended if you do not share greetings. People are disturbed by the isolation of visibly armed civilians, who number very few. And people do not understand the separation of religious rituals and holidays. The world is shared by the people within it, so why practice any act of distancing?</p><p>The city looks older in part due to its mistreatment. Plaster falls off homes, vines overtake facades, and half-finished construction projects leave massive holes in the ground with accompanying mounds of dirt. But while people make benches out of giant, useless concrete slabs and empty fruit boxes, they plug in airpods and sport new clothes, an anachronism of wealth.</p><p>I’m too tired to read this over, but I’m sure you get the gist of the city. We’re staying in a hotel for the night, but Sunday we’ll make out way to our host families.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the stars from the plane, gliding over the quiet Atlantic Ocean in the dead of night. As we pulled in
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How Big is a Home?</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/28/How-Big-is-a-Home/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/28/How-Big-is-a-Home/</id>
    <published>2019-12-29T02:09:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-29T02:16:25.650Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>Nick is standing 181 inches across from me in our 2 bedroom apartment that we’ve occupied for the last 6 months. We know the question that anyone who knows us is asking: <em>what’s happening to the brick?</em> Over the past few days we’ve packed up our winter gear, sent our intergalactic friend Yubba to the care of another home, and removed the plants from the windowsill. Our little apartment, with its quaint exposed brick, is is being left behind.</p><p>We’ve found two subletters, a cheerful German man studying music and a kind Italian doctor. We think we’ve left the place in good hands, but we will miss Woodlawn while we’re in Senegal.</p><p>Tonight, we’re heading to Chinatown to find gifts for the residents of our new home in Dakar. We have no idea what to get them. Hopefully, they will never read this blog. If you have any idea what a 31 year old Senegalese woman might like as a housewarming gift, please write us.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Forberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick is standing 181 inches across from me in our 2 bedroom apartment that we’ve occupied for the last 6 mo
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome!</title>
    <link href="https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/27/Welcome/"/>
    <id>https://peterforberg.github.io/2019/12/27/Welcome/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T08:37:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-27T10:20:20.355Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="This-is-our-website"><a href="#This-is-our-website" class="headerlink" title="This is our website"></a>This is our website</h1><p><em>Peter Forberg</em></p><p>We have decided to document our time in Senegal with a blog. We know it’s been done before, by people who are smarter and better than us, but I spent a lot of time programming this site to look nice using hexo.js, GitHub, and Markdown, and I need to get something out of it. We don’t know what we’ll post about here. Probably just food Nick likes, poems I find, and…well…I tried to think of a third thing but honestly that’s about it.</p><p>I don’t know how to code well. So don’t expect too much. Nick will probably ask me to put in something ridiculous, like animated chihuahua that barks out “NICK” when you click it. I can’t do that. I’m only human. And I’m majoring in sociology. Anyways, if there’s something you’d particularly like to see on this blog, just send us a message. I’m sure you know how to contact one of us.</p><p>This post?</p><h2 id="It’s-mostly-just-a-way-to-test-Markdown"><a href="#It’s-mostly-just-a-way-to-test-Markdown" class="headerlink" title="It’s mostly just a way to test Markdown"></a>It’s mostly just a way to test Markdown</h2><p>Actually, I’m writing it at <strong>four AM</strong> because I want it to go live before we leave on a plane. We haven’t even decided on a URL. I don’t know how it looks on mobile. See you in the next one. Placeholder text.</p><p>If you find any out of place Chinese text please let me know. It’s a process.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;This-is-our-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#This-is-our-website&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;This is our website&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is our website&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;e
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
